Guide to the Doty and Young family papers 1977.203
Brooklyn Historical Society
Doty and Young family papers
1765-1910
1840-1880
Brooklyn Historical Society
Young, Henry D.
Doty, Isaac
Doty, Richard
1977.203
0.5 Linear Feet in one manuscript box and one oversize folder.
This collection includes mortgages, deeds, and agreements relating to various Brooklyn properties owned by Henry D. Young (1841-1884).
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source and date of acquisition unknown. Formally accessioned in 1977.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by family member, subject, and chronologically.
Biographical Note
Isaac Doty (1764-1824) married Elizabeth Williams (1760-1820) in 1782. Isaac was the executor of the estate of Thomas Williams, Elizabeth's father, who was a New York City merchant. He was also a proprietor of Doty and Seaman Company, a hardware company, which was established between 1797 and 1801, and Doty, Willets, and Company, a brewery, which was established in 1806. Richard Doty (1783-1852), the son of Isaac, lived in New York City and Brooklyn. He worked with Doty, Willets, and Company and later became Ferry master for the Union Ferry Company. Elizabeth Doty (1810-1862), the daughter of Richard, married Henry D. Young (1841-1884), who was a Brooklyn grocer. Their son, Charles T. Young, was a Brooklyn businessman.
Related Materials
Isaac Doty papers, 1797-1823 (1977.495)
Joseph Doty and Jacob Seaman deed (1977.477)
Vincent Tilyou, Mary Tilyou, and Richard Doty deed (1977.496)
William Mott inventory of goods and chattels (1977.485)
Scope and Contents
This collection includes mortgages, deeds, and agreements relating to various Brooklyn properties owned by Henry D. Young. There are also receipts and account books and programs and invitations that pertain to events in Brooklyn. Additional materials include two bank books, deeds, and legal papers of Isaac Doty; an account book for the estate of Thomas Williams; several account books, deeds, certificates and legal papers related to Richard Doty; a notebook of personal accounts with loose papers of the Young and Doty families; a recipe book; invitations and programs of Charles T. Young; and documents regarding the Brooklyn real estate of Henry D. Young.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.
Recipes; Financial records; Account books; Invitations; Programs (documents); Real property |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Land titles |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Deeds; Legal documents; Family papers; Genealogy; Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Certificates; Young, Henry D.; Doty, Isaac; Doty, Richard
- Isaac and Richard Doty property records - Queens County, 1765, 1802-1828 (Box OS-34)
- Receipts from 1791-1794 Isaac Doty account book, 1788-1815 (Box 1)
- Isaac Doty account book, 1791-1794 (Box 1)
- Isaac and Richard Doty account book, circa 1794-1828 (Box 1)
- Doty and Seaman account book, 1797 (Box 1)
- Thomas Williams estate account book by Isaac Doty, 1799-1807 (Box 1)
- Isaac Doty and Bank of New York account book, 1799-1815 (Box 1)
- Isaac Doty documents, 1799, 1819 (Box 1)
- Isaac Doty and Manhattan Company account book, 1800-1811 (Box 1)
- Richard Doty certificates, 1805-1807 (Box OS-34)
  Scope and Contents
  Firemen of the City of New York, 18 April 1805. Certificate to Richard Doty. Signed: T. Woodman, Clerk.
  Richard Doty appointed fireman, City of New York, 8 June 1807.
- Richard Doty documents, 1818-1839 (Box 1)
  Public cartman certificate, 1818, and receipt, 1839.
- Henry D. Young property records - 21 Cheapside Street (Manhattan), 1817 (Box OS-34)
  Biographical / Historical
  Cheapside Street was renamed Hamilton Street in 1827. The city sold it to the developers of Knickerbocker Village in 1933 and it no longer exists.
- Henry D. Young property records - Middagh Street, 1828 (Box OS-34)
- Henry D. Young property records - 24 Prospect Street, 1841-1875 (Box OS-34)
- Henry D. Young property records - 13 Atlantic Avenue, 1843-1885 (Box OS-34)
- Henry D. Young property records - 77 Fulton Street, 1849 (Box 1)
- Henry D. Young property records - 104 State Street, 1855-1886 (Box 1)
- Henry D. Young property records - 26 Lafayette Avenue, 1861 (Box 1)
- Henry D. Young documents, 1854-circa 1860s (Box 1)
  Receipt, 1854, and undated blank property indenture form.
- Programs and invitations, 1883-1910 (Box 1)
  Brooklyn Bridge opening ceremonies, 1883; 50th anniversary of the incorporation of the City of Brooklyn, 1884; Statue of Liberty inauguration, 1886; and more. Addressed to both Henry D. Young and Charles T. Young.
- Recipe book, circa 1900 (Box 1)